A Register of the Américo Ghioldi Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Speeches and Writings, 1919-1982.
  - "Como leer al Papa," La Vanguardia., 1982 June 18 (Folder 28: 10)
  - "El libro blanco de la guerra," La Vanguardia., 1982 June 18 (Folder 28: 11)
  - "Opina el Dr. Américo Ghioldi," Ideas., 1982 June 21 (Folder 28: 12)
  - "De lo muerto y de lo vivo de la realidad," La Vanguardia., 1982 June 25 (Folder 28: 13)
  - "Mensaje de Américo Ghioldi," La Vanguardia., 1982 June 19 (Folder 28: 14)
  - "Hayek, economista y utopista," A Fondo., 1982 July (Folder 28: 15)
  - "El ejército y los socialistas," La Vanguardia., 1982 July 2 (Folder 28: 16)
  - "Pensar en los fundamentos de la Argentina de la mañanas," La Vanguardia., 1982 July 2 (Folder 28: 17)
  - "Sentido común y los hechos fundamentales," La Vanguardia., 1982 July 16 (Folder 28: 18)
  - "Llegar a la normalidad para quedarnos con ella. No para volver a las andadas," La Vanguardia., 1982 July 23 (Folder 28: 19)
  - "¿A dónde vamos? ¿Pero de dónde venimos?", La Vanguardia., 1982 July 30 (Folder 28: 20)
  - "Para conquistar el orden constitucional y bien guardarlo," La Vanguardia., 1982 August 6 (Folder 28: 21)
  - "Reconstruir la normalidad institucional," La voz del interior., 1982 August 6 (Folder 28: 22)
  - "Américo Ghioldi habla para Crónica," Crónica., 1982 August 13 (Folder 28: 23)
  - "Sueños y pesadillas en política y economía nacional," La Vanguardia., 1982 August 27 (Folder 28: 24)
  - "Medidas para evitar dificultades y nuevas frustraciones," La Vanguardia., 1982 September 3 (Folder 28: 25)
  - "República y establidad difíciles," La Vanguardia., 1982 September 10 (Folder 28: 26)
  - "Investigar los monopolios," La Vanguardia., 1982 September 17 (Folder 28: 27)
  - "Radicales y frondicistas piden al gobierno la supresión de la representación proporcional," La Vanguardia., 1982 September 24 (Folder 28: 28)
  - "Sueños del viejo y de la vieja," La Vanguardia., 1982 September 24 (Folder 28: 29)
  - "No veo posibilidad de un golpe militar," El Litoral., 1982 September 29 (Folder 28: 30)
  - "Guerra de las Malvinas: el programa socialista," La Vanguardia., 1982 October 1 (Folder 28: 31)
  - "El fresco, prototipo de política criolla," La Vanguardia., 1982 October 8 (Folder 28: 32)
  - "El atavismo de la política argentina," La Vanguardia., 1982 October 29 (Folder 28: 33)
  - "De jueves a jueves," La Vanguardia., 1982 October 29 (Folder 28: 34)
  - "El problema del Beagle deberá tratarlo el próximo gobierno constitucional," La Vanguardia., 1982 October 29 (Folder 28: 35)
  - "De jueves a jueves," La Vanguardia., 1982 November 5 (Folder 28: 36)
  - "Recrear y promover las soluciones y actitudes constructivas," La Vanguardia., 1982 November 5 (Folder 28: 37)
  - "¡A la cosa! argentinos," La Vanguardia., 1982 November 19 (Folder 28: 38)
  - "De jueves a jueves," La Vanguardia., 1982 November 19 (Folder 28: 39)
  - "Basta de juegos políticos," La Vanguardia., 1982 November 26 (Folder 28: 40)
  - "De jueves a jueves," La Vanguardia., 1982 November 26 (Folder 28: 41)
  - "De jueves a jueves," La Vanguardia., 1982 December 10 (Folder 28: 42)
  - "El enredo y los desenredadores," La Vanguardia., 1982 December 10 (Folder 28: 43)
  - "Américo Ghioldi propone una alianza de centro-izquierda," La Vanguardia., 1982 December 18 (Folder 28: 44)
- Diaries and notebooks, 1917-1981.
  Arranged chronologically
  - Undated (Folder 28: 45-48)
  - 1917 (Box-folder 29: 1)
  - 1919 (Folder 29: 2)
  - 1939-1941 (Folder 29: 3)
  - 1951 (Folder 29: 4)
  - 1952 (Folder 29: 5)
  - 1953 (Folder 29: 6)
  - 1953-1957 (Folder 29: 7)
  - 1954 (Folder 29: 8)
  - 1955 (Box-folder 30: 1)
  - 1956 (Folder 30: 2-3)
  - 1964-1968 (Folder 30: 4)
  - 1971 (Folder 30: 5)
  - 1972 (Folder 30: 6)
  - 1973 (Folder 30: 7)
  - 1974-1975 (Folder 30: 8)
  - 1974-1976 (Box-folder 31: 1)
  - 1975-1976 (Folder 31: 2)
  - 1977-1978 (Folder 31: 3)
  - 1977-1979 (Folder 31: 4)
  - 1979 (Folder 31: 5-6)
  - 1980 (Folder 31: 7)
  - 1980 (Box-folder 32: 1)
  - 1980-1981 (Folder 32: 2)
- Lecture notes, 1919-1981.
  - Undated (Folder 32: 3-4)
  - 1919/1925 (Folder 32: 5)
  - 1928-1933 (Folder 32: 6)
  - 1934-1935 (Folder 32: 7)
  - 1936-1937 (Folder 32: 8)
  - 1938 (Folder 32: 9)
  - 1939 (Folder 32: 10)
  - 1941 (Folder 32: 11)
  - 1942-1943 (Folder 32: 12)
  - 1944-1945 (Box-folder 33: 1)
  - 1946 (Folder 33: 2)
  - 1947-1948 (Folder 33: 3)
  - 1949 (Folder 33: 4)
  - 1950 (Folder 33: 5)
  - 1951-1954 (Folder 33: 6)
  - 1955 (Folder 33: 7)
  - 1956 (Folder 33: 8)
  - 1957 (Folder 33: 9)
  - 1958 (Folder 33: 10)
  - 1959 (Folder 33: 11)
  - 1960 (Folder 33: 12)
  - 1961 (Box-folder 34: 1-2)
  - 1962 (Folder 34: 3)
  - 1963 (Folder 34: 4)
  - 1964 (Folder 34: 5)
  - 1965-1966 (Folder 34: 6)
  - 1967 (Folder 34: 7)
  - 1968 (Folder 34: 8)
  - 1969-1970 (Folder 34: 9)
  - 1971-1972 (Folder 34: 10)
  - 1973-1976 (Folder 34: 11)
  - 1977-1980 (Folder 34: 12)
  - 1981 (Folder 34: 13)
- Study guides, 1959-1965.
  - Undated (Folder 34: 14)
  - 1959 (Box-folder 35: 1)
  - 1961 (Folder 35: 2)
  - 1962 (Folder 35: 3)
  - 1965 (Folder 35: 4)
- Conference materials, 1959-1986.
  Includes correspondence, papers, proposals, reports and working documents, arranged chronologically by conference
  - Jornadas Interuniversitarias sobre Enseñanza Media, Bahia Blanca, Argentina, 1960 November 6-12
    - Correspondence, 1960 (Folder 35: 5)
    - Credential, 1960 (Folder 35: 6)
    - Papers, 1960 (Folder 35: 7-9)
    - Programs, 1960 (Folder 35: 10)
    - Reports and working documents
      - 1959 (Folder 35: 11)
      - 1960 (Folder 35: 12)
    - Resolutions, 1960 (Folder 35: 13)
    - Statistics, 1960 (Folder 35: 14)
  - Primer Foro de Partidos Politicos Democráticos Latinoamericanos, Buenos Aires, Argentina, 1986 November 27-29
    - Lists of participants, 1986 (Folder 35: 15)
    - Proposals, 1986 (Folder 35: 16)
- Card files, 1963-1980. (Box 36-38)
  Notecards with citations and annotations on history, politics, and philosophy
- Political career file, 1925-1966. (Box 39)
  Includes bulletins, correspondence, records of proceedings, and reports and statistics, arranged chronologically by political office
  - Concejo Deliberante de la Ciudad de Buenos Aires, 1925-1933
    - Bulletins, 1925; 1932 (Folder 39: 1)
    - Correspondence, 1930-1933 (Folder 39: 2)
    - Record of proceedings, 1929 (Folder 39: 3)
    - Reports and statistics
      - 1925-1929 (Folder 39: 4)
      - 1933 (Folder 39: 5)
  - Camara de Deputados de la Nación Argentina, 1940-1966
    - Compilation of speeches, statements, and legislative proposals made by Ghioldi
      - Summary, Undated (Folder 39: 6)
      - 1964 (Folder 39: 7-9)
      - 1965 (Box-folder 40: 1-2)
      - 1966 (Folder 40: 3)
    - Constitution, 1942 (Folder 40: 4)
    - Record of proceedings
      - 1940 (Folder 40: 5-6)
      - 1941 (Folder 40: 7)
      - 1941 (Box-folder 41: 1-2)
      - 1946 (Folder 41: 3)
      - 1960 (Folder 41: 4)
      - 1964 (Folder 41: 5-6)
      - 1965 (Folder 41: 7)
      - 1966 (Folder 41: 8)
    - Reports, 1964-1966 (Folder 41: 9)
- Subject file, 1857-1981. (Box 42)
  Includes clippings, pamphlets, and reports, arranged alphabetically by subject
  - Alberdi, Juan Bautista, 1952 (Folder 42: 1)
  - Alcoholism—France, 1954-1955 (Folder 42: 2)
  - Aramburu, Pedro Eugenio, 1977-1980 (Folder 42: 3)
  - Araquistàin, Luis, 1961 (Folder 42: 4)
  - Argentina—Economic conditions, 1955-1966 (Folder 42: 5)
  - Argentina—Foreign relations—Chile, 1981 (Folder 42: 6)
  - Argentina—Politics and government
    - 1942-1956 (Folder 42: 7)
    - 1960-1970 (Folder 42: 8)
    - 1971 (Folder 42: 9)
    - 1978-1979 (Folder 42: 10)
  - Argentina—Social conditions, 1960-1962 (Folder 42: 11)
  - Armed forces—Argentina, 1964 (Folder 42: 12)
  - Bessaso, Manuel V., 1963 (Box-folder 43: 1)
  - Besteiro, Julián, 1962 (Folder 43: 2)
  - Borges, Jorge Luis, 1986 (Folder 43: 3)
  - Buenos Aires (city), 1931-1961 (Folder 43: 4)
  - Buenos Aires (province), 1870-1877 (Folder 43: 5)
  - Catholic church
    - 1924-1953 (Folder 43: 6)
    - 1954-1960 (Folder 43: 7)
  - Census—Argentina, 1960 (Folder 43: 8)
  - Chaco province (Argentina), 1957 (Folder 43: 9)
  - Communism, 1952-1953 (Folder 43: 10)
  - Comparative government, 1955-1957 (Folder 43: 11)
  - Constitution—Argentina (Box 44)
    - 1941-1949 (Folder 44: 1)
    - 1955 (Folder 44: 2)
    - 1956 (Folder 44: 3)
    - 1957 (Folder 44: 4-7)
    - 1958-1976 (Folder 44: 8)
  - Contursi, Carlos, 1965 (Folder 44: 9)
  - Corrientes province (Argentina), 1960 (Folder 44: 10)
  - Croce, Benedetto
    - 1952 (Folder 44: 11-12)
    - 1953-1954 (Folder 44: 13)
  - Djilas, Milovan, 1954 (Box-folder 45: 1)
  - Education—Argentina
    - Undated (Folder 45: 2)
    - 1860-1905 (Folder 45: 3-4)
    - 1919-1929 (Folder 45: 5)
    - 1930-1939 (Folder 45: 6)
    - 1940-1949 (Folder 45: 7)
    - 1950-1955 (Folder 45: 8)
    - 1956 (Folder 45: 9)
    - 1957 (Folder 45: 10)
    - 1958 (Box-folder 46: 1)
    - 1959 (Folder 46: 2-3)
    - 1960 (Folder 46: 4-5)
    - 1961 (Folder 46: 6)
    - 1962 (Folder 46: 7-9)
    - 1963 (Box-folder 47: 1-2)
    - 1964 (Folder 47: 3-4)
    - 1965-1966 (Folder 47: 5)
    - 1978-1979 (Folder 47: 6)
  - Education—France, 1959-1962 (Folder 47: 7)
  - Education—Great Britain, 1939 (Folder 47: 8)
  - Education—Italy, 1958 (Folder 47: 9)
  - Education—Norway, 1955 (Folder 47: 10)
  - Education—Soviet Union
    - 1958 (Folder 47: 11)
    - 1959 (Folder 47: 12)
  - Education—Sweden, 1958 (Folder 47: 13)
  - Education—United States, 1956-1958 (Folder 47: 14)
  - Fitte, Rodolfo A., 1973 (Folder 47: 15)
  - Gelderen, Adolfo Manuel van, 1934 (Folder 47: 16)
  - Germany—Economic conditions, 1961-1977 (Folder 47: 17)
  - González, Joaquín V., 1962-1963 (Box-folder 48: 1)
  - Inda, Rufino, 1963-1964 (Folder 48: 2)
  - Iramain, Julio González, 1965 (Folder 48: 3)
  - Jaurès, Jean, 1911-1959 (Folder 48: 4)
  - Jehovah's Witnesses, 1976-1980 (Folder 48: 5)
  - Justo, Andrés, 1963 (Folder 48: 6)
  - Justo, Juan B.
    - 1931-1965 (Folder 48: 7)
    - 1980 (Folder 48: 8)
  - López Rega, José, 1975 (Folder 48: 9)
  - Machiavelli, Niccolò, 1941-1956 (Folder 48: 10)
  - Mantovani, 1961 (Folder 48: 11)
  - Meabe, Tomàs, 1964 (Folder 48: 12)
  - Mitre, Bartolomé, 1956 (Folder 48: 13)
  - Monetary system—Argentina, 1927-1971 (Folder 48: 14)
  - Montoneros, 1981 (Folder 48: 15)
  - Oddone, Jacinto, 1961-1966 (Box-folder 49: 1)
  - Palacios, Alfredo, 1960 (Folder 49: 2)
  - Partido Socialista, 1936-1953 (Folder 49: 3)
  - Partido Socialista Democrático, 1962-1975 (Folder 49: 4)
  - Payró, Roberto J., 1962 (Folder 49: 5)
  - Peron, Eva Duarte, 1946-1947 (Folder 49: 6)
  - Petroleum industry—Argentina
    - 1957 (Folder 49: 7)
  - Poverty, 1965-1969 (Folder 49: 8-9)
  - Pradal, Gabriel, 1965 (Folder 49: 12)
  - Prieto, Indalecio, 1962 (Folder 49: 13)
  - Protestantism—Argentina, 1957 (Folder 49: 14)
  - Repetto, Nicolás (Box 50)
    - 1937-1964 (Folder 50: 1)
    - 1965-1966 (Folder 50: 2)
  - Rosas, Juan Manuel, 1857 (Folder 50: 3)
  - Rousseau, Jean-Jacques, 1925 (Folder 50: 4)
  - Saragat, Giuseppe, 1965 (Folder 50: 5-6)
  - Sarmiento, Domingo Faustino, 1874-1961 (Folder 50: 7)
  - Science and technology, 1957-1958 (Folder 50: 8)
  - Socialism, 1933-1954 (Folder 50: 9)
  - Solari, Juan Antonio, 1973 (Folder 50: 10)
  - Spain—Politics and government, 1949-1967 (Folder 50: 11)
  - Trade unions—Sweden, 1963 (Folder 50: 12)
  - Weygand, Maxime, 1950 (Folder 50: 13)
  - Zola, Emile, 1935 (Folder 50: 14)
- Writings by others, 1895-1981.
  Arranged alphabetically by author
  - Alonso, Rodolfo V., 1962 (Folder 50: 15)
  - Alvarez, Serafín, 1895 (Folder 50: 16)
  - Antoni, Carlo, 1951-1955 (Folder 50: 17)
  - Aristarco, (?), Undated (Folder 50: 18)
  - Benjamin, Harold R. W., Undated (Folder 50: 19)
  - Bravo, Héctor Félix, 1962 (Box-folder 51: 1)
  - Brunot-Gybal, Henriette, Undated (Folder 51: 2)
  - Campobassi, J. S., 1960 (Folder 51: 3)
  - Díaz, Pedro
    - Undated (Folder 51: 4)
    - 1957 (Folder 51: 5)
  - Díaz Doin, Guillermo
    - Undated (Folder 51: 6)
    - 1960-1961 (Folder 51: 7)
  - Fay, Victor, 1968-1970 (Folder 51: 8)
  - Fernández, Guillermo, 1957 (Folder 51: 9)
  - Franchini, Raffaello, 1951-1954 (Folder 51: 10)
  - Germinal, Roland, 1958 (Folder 51: 11)
  - Gervasi, Frank, 1942 (Folder 51: 12)
  - Ghioldi, Alfredo M., 1965 (Folder 51: 13)
  - González, Dora Elba and Julia Susana Leive, 1962 (Folder 51: 14)
  - Guglialmelli, Juan Enrique, 1972 (Folder 51: 15)
  - Incarnato, Arístides A., 1970 (Folder 51: 16)
  - Justo, Juan B. (Box 52)
    - 1912-1913 (Folder 52: 1)
    - 1914-1915 (Folder 52: 2)
    - 1916-1918 (Folder 52: 3)
    - 1920 (Folder 52: 4)
    - 1921 (Folder 52: 5)
    - 1922-1923 (Folder 52: 6)
    - 1924-1925 (Folder 52: 7)
    - 1926 (Folder 52: 8)
  - Laski, Harold, Undated (Folder 52: 9)
  - Lefebvre, Henri, 1971 (Folder 52: 10)
  - Linares Quintana, Segundo V., 1952 (Folder 52: 11)
  - Mérega, Herminia A. T., Undated (Folder 52: 12)
  - Nicolini, Fausto, 1949-1954 (Box-folder 53: 1)
  - Oddone, Jacinto, 1955 (Folder 53: 2)
  - Pan, Luis, 1949 (Folder 53: 3)
  - Pardo, Raymundo, 1958-1959 (Folder 53: 4)
  - Pena, José Luis, Undated (Folder 53: 5)
  - Pérez Bravo, Eugenio, Undated (Folder 53: 6)
  - Perez Catán, Mauricio, 1958 (Folder 53: 7)
  - Repetto, Nicolás
    - 1928-1934 (Folder 53: 8)
    - 1935-1936 (Folder 53: 9)
    - 1937 (Folder 53: 10)
    - 1938-1939 (Folder 53: 11)
    - 1940-1941 (Folder 53: 12)
  - Rojas, Isaac Francisco
    - 1978 (Folder 53: 13)
    - 1981 (Folder 53: 14)
  - Romántico, Educador, 1966 (Folder 53: 15)
  - Rosenberg, Bernard, 1962 (Folder 53: 16)
  - Rosenfeld, Oreste, 1952 (Folder 53: 17)
  - Sánchez Viamonte, Carlos, 1955 (Folder 53: 18)
  - Serini, Paolo, 1952-1954 (Folder 53: 19)
  - Téson, Néstor Eduardo, 1966 (Folder 53: 20)
  - Weber, Alfredo, 1948 (Folder 53: 21)
- Printed matter, 1898-1994. (Box 54)
  Monographs, pamphlets, and serial issues, largely relating to Argentine politics, arranged alphabetically by physical form and chronologically thereunder
  - Monographs, 1898-1964
    - 1898 (Folder 54: 1)
    - 1916 (Folder 54: 2)
    - 1935 (Folder 54: 3)
    - 1936 (Folder 54: 4)
    - 1954 (Folder 54: 5)
    - 1956 (Folder 54: 6)
    - 1957 (Folder 54: 7)
    - 1958 (Folder 54: 8)
    - 1961 (Folder 54: 9-10)
    - 1963 (Folder 54: 11)
    - 1964 (Folder 54: 12)
  - Pamphlets, 1900-1983 (Box 55)
    - Undated (Folder 55: 1)
    - 1900-1915 (Folder 55: 2)
    - 1923-1931 (Folder 55: 3)
    - 1932-1936 (Folder 55: 4)
    - 1937-1939 (Folder 55: 5)
    - 1940-1941 (Folder 55: 6)
    - 1944-1945 (Folder 55: 7)
    - 1946-1947 (Folder 55: 8)
    - 1948 (Folder 55: 9)
    - 1950-1954 (Folder 55: 10)
    - 1955-1956 (Box-folder 56: 1)
    - 1957 (Folder 56: 2)
    - 1958-1959 (Folder 56: 3)
    - 1960-1963 (Folder 56: 4)
    - 1965 (Folder 56: 5)
    - 1966-1969 (Folder 56: 6)
    - 1970-1971 (Folder 56: 7)
    - 1975 (Folder 56: 8)
    - 1975 (Box-folder 57: 1)
    - 1976-1978 (Folder 57: 2)
    - 1980-1983 (Folder 57: 3)
  - Serial issues, 1931—1994
    - General
      - 1931-1949 (Folder 57: 4)
      - 1950-1957 (Folder 57: 5)
      - 1958-1959 (Folder 57: 6)
      - 1961-1962 (Folder 57: 7)
      - 1963-1984 (Folder 57: 8)
    - Cabildo
      - 1975 February – 1976 December (Folder 57: 9)
      - 1977 May/June, December (Folder 57: 10)
      - 1978 (Box 58)
        - February-, May/June (Folder 58: 1)
        - July-December (Folder 58: 2)
      - 1979
        - January/February, June (Folder 58: 3)
        - August-November (Folder 58: 4)
      - 1980
        - January-June (Folder 58: 5)
        - July-November (Folder 58: 6)
      - 1981
        - January-June (Folder 58: 7)
        - July-December (Folder 58: 8)
      - 1982
        - January-, June/July (Folder 58: 9)
        - August-December (Folder 58: 10)
      - 1983 February-May (Box-folder 59: 1)
      - 1984 January-March (Folder 59: 2)
    - Consigna Nacional
      - 1974
        - February-March (Folder 59: 3)
        - April-May (Folder 59: 4)
        - June-November (Folder 59: 5)
    - Crisis
      - 1973 May-December (Folder 59: 6)
      - 1974 (Box 60)
        - January-March (Folder 60: 1)
        - April-June (Folder 60: 2)
        - July-October (Folder 60: 3)
        - November-December (Folder 60: 4)
      - 1975
        - January-March (Folder 60: 5)
        - April-June (Box-folder 61: 1)
        - July-September (Folder 61: 2)
        - October-December (Folder 61: 3)
      - 1976
        - January-February (Folder 61: 4)
        - March-April (Folder 61: 5)
        - May-June (Folder 61: 6)
        - July-August (Folder 61: 7)
    - Cuarto Poder, nos. 3, 5-6, and supplement, 1972 (Box-folder 62: 1)
    - Indice
      - 1949 December (Folder 62: 2)
      - 1950 May/June, -October/November (Folder 62: 3)
    - Los Libros
      - 1970 January-July (Folder 62: 4)
      - 1971 June-November (Folder 62: 5)
      - 1972
        - January-May (Folder 62: 6)
        - July-September (Folder 62: 7)
      - 1973 March/April, -August/September (Folder 62: 8)
      - 1975 May/June (Folder 62: 9)
    - La Opinión
      - 1977
        - June 5-26 (Folder 62: 10)
        - July 10-August 26 (Folder 62: 11)
      - 1978 May-July (Folder 62: 12)
    - Panorama (Box 63)
      - 1976 July (Folder 63: 1)
      - 1977
        - March-June (Folder 63: 2)
        - July-August (Folder 63: 3)
        - September-October (Folder 63: 4)
    - Restauración, 1975 June – 1976 February (Folder 63: 5)
    - La Vanguardia
      - 1964 March 11 – 1965 March 10 (Folder 63: 6)
      - 1970 July 22 – 1974 November 4 (Folder 63: 7)
      - 1980 March 27-July 24 (Folder 63: 8)
      - Commemorative yearbook, 1994 December (Folder 63: 9)
    - La Voz, 1988 March-December (Folder 63: 10)
- Photographs, 1960-2006. (Box 64)
  Prints depiciting Ghioldi and his library, arranged chronologically
  - Two prints depicting Américo Ghioldi, Undated (Folder 64: 1)
  - One print depicting Américo Ghioldi and other delegates to a conference on education, Bahía Blanca, Argentina (Folder 64: 2)
  - One print depicting Américo Ghioldi with a group of his students, circa 1965 (Folder 64: 3)
  - Six prints depicting Américo Ghioldi addressing a political meeting, circa 1970 (Folder 64: 4)
  - Eleven prints depiciting Américo Ghioldi's library, Buenos Aires, Argentina, 2006 (Folder 64: 5)
- Sound recordings, 1977-2006.
  Compact sound cassettes largely containing interviews with, and talks by, Ghioldi, arranged chronologically
  - List of recordings compiled by Ghioldi's son, Américo, 2006 (Folder 64: 6)
  - Recordings by Américo Ghioldi
    - "Plan de Salida," Lisbon, Portugal, 1977 February 2. (Folder 64: 7)
      Proposals concerning Argentine political crisis. One compact sound cassette
    - "Los 80 años," interview conducted by Sr. Lestany, 1979 May. (Folder 64: 8-9)
      Two compact sound cassettes
    - Interview conducted by Somos review, 1980. (Folder 64: 10)
      One compact sound cassette
    - Interview conducted by Michel Pache of Journal du soir, 1980 June 10, and interview, Radio Provincia, 1981 July. (Folder 64: 11)
    - Press conference, Rosario, Argentina, 1980 September. (Folder 64: 12)
    - "La dura construcción de 1880," 1980 November and interview, Radio Rivadavia, 1981 July 11. (Folder 64: 13)
    - Interview, Radio Rivadavia, 1981 June 24. (Folder 64: 14)
    - "El revisionismo histórico ahora, acerca del 45,", 1981 November 21. (Folder 64: 15)
    - Interview, La Nación, 1982 March 30, and interview, TV Globo, 1982 April 27. (Folder 64: 16)
  - Others
    - Talk by Nicolás Repetto, Undated. (Folder 64: 17)
    - Interview with Carlos Burone, 1983 January. (Folder 64: 18-19)
- Oversize materials, 1913-1975. (Box 65)
  Includes serial issues, scrapbooks, and other materials, arranged by physical form
  - Watercolor by unknown artist, 1947 (Folder 65: 1)
  - Diploma awarded to Américo Ghioldi, Unión Cultural Americana, Buenos Aires, Argentina, 1975 June 19 (Folder 65: 2)
  - Serial issues
    - Afirmación, 1961 October 18-25 (Folder 65: 3-4)
    - La Causa Peronista, 1974 September 3 (Folder 65: 5)
    - Communauté européenne, 1962 June (Folder 65: 6)
    - Consigna, 1974 September 30 (Folder 65: 7)
    - Cronica, 1974 June 4-July 2 (Folder 65: 8-9)
    - La Nación, 1974 July 2-5 (Folder 65: 10-13)
    - Resistencia, 1950 August (Folder 65: 14)
  - Testimony of appreciation signed by Ghioldi's colleagues, 1951 May 24 (Box-folder 66: 1)
  - Photostats of articles relating to the archdiocese of Buenos Aires, 1924-1926 (Folder 66: 2)
  - Scrapbooks containing articles from La Prensa, 1913-1927 (Folder 66: 3-4)